Friends, in today's video, I'm going to tell you
both online and offline
methods for canceling an ICICI Life Insurance policy. You'll notice that
whenever you want to take out a life insurance policy, the
bank employee
or advisor comes to your house and
fills out the form for you. However,
when it comes to cancellation, no one helps.
Sometimes, the
right information doesn't reach you.
Friends,
I've come up with a solution to this problem in today's video.
So, if you find this video
helpful,
please like this video and subscribe to the channel
so that the YouTube algorithm can help it reach everyone it
needs. Friends, in this video,
I've covered all the methods
you'll likely encounter. However, if
you have any doubts about which method is
applicable to your case, please
share your experience in the comments section.
I will
reply to yours as soon as possible and help you with
this.  Our other
viewers will also learn something new from this experience,
so I hope you'll
definitely share your experiences. So
friends, let me take you to the computer screen. Just like when
you
buy something on Amazon, you're
given 5 to 10 days to
thoroughly
inspect the product. If you feel it's
not right for you,
you can return it and get a full refund.
Similarly, according to ID rules, you
can cancel any life insurance policy within 15 days and get a refund. This
period is called the free look period. The
free look period is normally 15
days. However, if you've purchased the policy
online or through a mobile application,
you get 30 days
within which you
can cancel the policy by filling out the last look period cancellation form.
I've
provided this form in the comment section and description,
if you'd like.  You
can visit the branch by filling it in. Here
you have to fill in the policy number in this form. If
your policy number has not been generated, then
you can also enter the policy application number here.
Here you mention your policy
holder's name, address, contact,
email address,
signature, etc. and also
fill in your bank account details
so that you can mention in which account your refund amount will
come. After
filling all these things here, you
can visit your nearest branch.
Locating the nearest branch is also very easy.
Here I
am pressing the click here button and you can see
it will be displayed here. Here
you will find the branch's address, its phone number
and the timing will also be
mentioned here. So you
can visit the branch by calling as per your convenient timing. Friends, now the
question arises that if you
cancel the policy during the freelo period, then do you have to pay
any charges.
Here friends, I would like to clarify to you
that if you have invested in a plan like ULIP
Where your money is
invested in the market, then in that case,
you will see the effect of fluctuations in the market in the returns.
If we assume that in the meantime, there has been a surge in the market, then it is
possible that you may get a return of an
amount more than the premium you have paid, that is,
you can make a profit. However,
if the market has gone
down a bit in the meantime, then you may
also incur a small loss.
We have many friends whose policy number has already been
generated, so
whatever black duty expenses they may have incurred in the meantime can
also be
deducted from your premium amount. Rest,
if there has been a medical conduct, then this medical
amount will also be related to this amount and the
remaining amount will be
given to you. Friends, I know
that 99% of us are such people who are
watching this video today
because their free look period has passed.
Forget 15 days or a month, 3
months, 6 months, 1 year, 3 years have passed since the
policy was signed.  If you want to cancel your policy today
and get your money refunded, then
friends, there is no need to panic.
I have covered the method for that
in this video. You
must watch the video till the end and if
you liked the explanation so far, then you must like this video
and subscribe to the channel.
Friends, before I
tell you the method of policy surrender, if you have
invested in a ULIP plan and you want to know
which method will be best for you if you stop the policy midway, then
this video is 'How to
Cancel ULIP Policy'. Definitely
click on it. Here I have given you
all the information related to ULIP policy cancellation.
You will find the link of this video in the description as well as
in the comment box. Now by
going there also you can get complete information related to ULIP policy cancellation.
Similarly, friends, if you have invested in an endowment
policy, money back policy or guaranteed return
policy, then
how much amount of return will you get in it,
I have completed it in a separate video.  I've
covered this method in detail, and I'll provide you with the link
in the comment section
above as well as in the description. Click here,
and you'll learn how much you'll get back if you
surrender your policy mid-term.
Similarly, I've covered how to cancel a term insurance policy
in a separate video, the link to which you'll find
in the comment section and in the description.
Now, you might wonder
why I didn't cover all these methods in this video. The
reason is simple, friends. All of you
watching this video have
different types of policies. To
avoid wasting your time,
I've
covered all three in separate videos. Go to whichever video is applicable to you
and
watch it so you don't waste time.
If you're wondering
which of these three videos you should watch based on your budget,
I'd suggest you
go to the comment section and mention the name of your plan,
such as ICICI Pru Future Perfect
Plan or ICICI Pru Lifetime.  Classic
Plan: Whatever your plan's name is,
mention it. I'll help you figure out
which criteria this plan
falls under and which
video you should watch accordingly. So, friends, now I'll
tell you
which apps you'll need to take to surrender your policy.
For this, first, you'll need to
download a surrender form. To download the surrender form,
click here and
press "Save" and you'll
see a page like this. Enter your policy number
and date of birth. As soon as you click "Download Form,"
you'll get a form similar to the "Free Look Period
Cancellation" form.
Fill in all your details in this form,
fill in the reason for surrender, and
take it to your nearest branch.
Whenever you go to the branch to surrender your policy, be
sure to bring these documents along with the surrender form: the
policy document, your photo ID
proof, such as your PAN card or Aadhaar card, and
a photocopy of the same.
If they ask for it, you can
take the photocopy and the original documents with you so that you can have them.
You can verify it and
also take your cancellation cheque
where your name is clearly mentioned so that the
surrender amount can be deposited in your account.
Friends, there are many of our friends
who were sold the policy with wrong information. The methods that
I have
discussed with you so far are those where the
policy was sent with correct information
but later the mind of the policy holder changed
and he no longer wants to continue in this plan due to which
he cancels it for free
or surrenders the policy. At the same time,
if you have been mis-sold or
defrauded, you went to HD and your
insurance was done or you
wanted to take a loan but due to pressure you had to
take a life insurance policy, then
in such cases, friends, you have been defrauded, so
if you want to resolve it, then stay tuned to this
video, otherwise you can accept this video
saying that you have been defrauded.
Here, the complaint can be released in three levels.
Many times,
you get a proper solution in the level one itself.  You get it,
hence you do
n't need to go to Level 1 or Level 3. To
raise a complaint at Level 1, there's a '
Click Here' button where you
can write and submit your entire complaint.
You can also directly
meet the Customer Service Officers at
your nearest ICICI
Prudential Life Insurance branch.
If you wish to lodge a complaint via email,
you
can email Lifeline@iciciprulife.com from your registered email ID. You can also call the
customer service
helpline number
1860266 776 from your registered number to release your grievances.
If
you don't receive a proper solution within the next 15 days,
or if you're
not satisfied with the solution provided, you
can directly go to Level 2 where
you'll speak to the Senior Vice President of
Customer Service, who will listen to your concerns
and
help provide a proper solution.  If
you are not satisfied with the solution there, then
you will go to level three.
Here you will
give your letter to the committee where you
will mention everything that has happened to you
and you will have to send it to this address.
You can note down this address in hard copy or you
can take a screenshot. If
you do not get any solution from there also, then you
can go to the insurance man. Now
you will ask what is an insurance man. Till now,
all the people with whom you have complained are employees of ICICI Prudential
only. The insurance
man is a person appointed by the government. On
one hand, you
can see that you
see the advertisement of Jago Grahak Jago where there is
a body to address the complaints of the customers, which has been
formed by the government. Here, if you
raise your complaint and if the
insurance feels that something
wrong has happened to you, then they will help you in getting a full refund.  Let's do it
friends, I
hope this video has helped you.
If it has helped you, then
please like the video and subscribe to the channel
and let me know in the comment section. If you
still have any doubts, I will
respond to you as soon as possible.